<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sean&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sean&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 23:05:27 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seanmcleod.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Camera Tracking of Aircraft Control Positions</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/06/camera-tracking-of-aircraft-control-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 23:05:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/06/camera-tracking-of-aircraft-control-positions/</guid>
      <description>The standard method of tracking the aircraft&amp;rsquo;s control positions as the pilot moves the controls for flight test instrumentation (FTI) purposes is to attach string potentiometers (string pots) to the control cables/rods. As the control cable/rod moves based on the pilot&amp;rsquo;s inputs a spring loaded thin steel wire is reeled in or out of the string pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extra 300 Spin</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/05/extra-300-spin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 23:36:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/05/extra-300-spin/</guid>
      <description>This is an example of the data collected by my Homebrew FTI (Flight Test Instrumentation) system during a spin in an Extra-300.
The control positions were tracked using a camera based tracking system that I developed and the output from the camera tracking units were fed into the FTI unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homebrew FTI</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/02/homebrew-fti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 23:50:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/02/homebrew-fti/</guid>
      <description>I first got involved in designing FTI equipment in 2008 when TFASA (Test Flying Academy of South Africa) asked me to design some FTI equipment to be used in a Hawker Hunter jet that they were using for a course they were running. I did a write-up on this work in - Geeks and Fast Jets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landing - Ground Effect, Flare - JSBSim</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/02/landing-ground-effect-flare-jsbsim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:36:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/02/landing-ground-effect-flare-jsbsim/</guid>
      <description>Taking a look at the ground effect and the flare on landing performance using JSBSim to see it&amp;rsquo;s effect on the final sink rate and the change in airspeed.
For this test I&amp;rsquo;m using the Boeing 737 model included with JSBSim. The aircraft is setup and trimmed at 150ft AGL with a speed of 140kt IAS and on a 3 degree flight path with the flaps and gear down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitch Rate Damping - JSBSim Test</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/02/pitch-rate-damping-jsbsim-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 10:25:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/02/pitch-rate-damping-jsbsim-test/</guid>
      <description>When an aircraft pitches up or down the tailplane rotates around the cg of the aircraft and this motion causes a change in the tailplane&amp;rsquo;s angle of attack, which generates a change in lift at the tailplane. This change in lift at the tailplane in conjunction with the tailplane&amp;rsquo;s arm from the cg generates an opposing, or damping, pitching moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max Q - Maximum Dynamic Pressure</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/01/max-q-maximum-dynamic-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 19:47:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2018/01/max-q-maximum-dynamic-pressure/</guid>
      <description>During a rocket launch the commentator will often call out &amp;ldquo;Max Q&amp;rdquo; at a specific point in time during the launch. This is the point at which the dynamic pressure acting on the rocket will be at it&amp;rsquo;s maximum.
The dynamic pressure or Q is the product of the air-density and the velocity squared of the object travelling through the air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelica - Simple Rocket Test</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2017/11/modelica-simple-rocket-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 11:00:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2017/11/modelica-simple-rocket-test/</guid>
      <description>In the mid 1980s while I was in high school my father bought me an Apple II, well actually a clone of an Apple II from Hong Kong. He had been a helicopter pilot in the air force and had then become an airline pilot, hence the Hong Kong connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MH-370 Forward Tracking</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2014/04/mh-370-forward-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 15:08:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2014/04/mh-370-forward-tracking/</guid>
      <description>The last reported location for MH-370 from Malaysian military radar is N6.6381 E96.408 at 18:22UTC. If we assume some maximum ground speed for the next 78 minutes until the 19:40UTC satellite ping then the intersection of the maximum aircraft range from the time of the last radar contact until the 19:40UTC satellite ping will define the northernmost and southernmost points on the 19:40UTC ping ring that the aircraft could have reached.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MH-370 Back Tracking</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2014/04/mh-370-back-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 15:58:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2014/04/mh-370-back-tracking/</guid>
      <description>For each ping between the aircraft and the Inmarsat satellite we have the range/elevation angle between the satellite at that time (satellite is moving) and the aircraft and we have the Burst Frequency Offset (BFO) Doppler data.
So the LOS speed between the satellite and the aircraft along the LOS vector is as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Photo Gallery People Tags</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2008/10/live-photo-gallery-people-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 17:30:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2008/10/live-photo-gallery-people-tags/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve used the tagging feature in the original Windows Vista Photo Gallery and the Windows Live Photo Gallery versions for tagging people in photos and the location of the photo.
The latest version of Windows Live Photo Gallery now includes a specific &amp;lsquo;People&amp;rsquo; category separate from the generic tags category for identifying people in photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitmap Snapshots of WPF Visuals</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2008/10/bitmap-snapshots-of-wpf-visuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 17:46:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2008/10/bitmap-snapshots-of-wpf-visuals/</guid>
      <description>Recently I needed to create a bitmap of some WPF controls to be used in another program. Doing a quick search turned up references to the RenderTargetBitmap class in WPF with sample code along the lines of:
RenderTargetBitmap bmp = new RenderTargetBitmap((int)element.Width, (int)element.Height, 96, 96, PixelFormats.Pbgra32); bmp.Render(element); However if the WPF control had a margin then the rendered bitmap had transparent pixels for the margin area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geeks and Fast Jets</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2008/06/geeks-and-fast-jets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 15:50:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2008/06/geeks-and-fast-jets/</guid>
      <description>I was approached recently to help develop some Flight Test Instrumentation (FTI) for a Hawker Hunter jet to be used during a test pilot course involving high angle of attack manoeuvres and spinning.
The following data needed to be recorded:
 Angle of Attack (AoA) Angle of Sideslipe (AoS) Attitude (pitch, roll and heading) Indicated airspeed and altitude Stick and rudder position GPS Video  In addition to recording all the data listed above they also wanted to display a subset of the data in the cockpit as an aid for spin recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MapReduce Implementation Using C# Generics</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/mapreduce-implementation-using-csharp-generics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 17:57:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/mapreduce-implementation-using-csharp-generics/</guid>
      <description>I came across the Google paper on MapReduce again the other day and decided to try a simple implementation using C# generics allowing you to specify specific types for the keys and values as opposed to being forced to use strings for all keys and values.
The initial version doesn&amp;rsquo;t include any automatic parallelism across multiple CPUs or clusters of machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Dynamic Range (HDR) Photo Test</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/high-dynamic-range-photo-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2007 21:13:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/high-dynamic-range-photo-test/</guid>
      <description>I started playing around with generating HDR photos. Here is one of my first attempts using our Pentax DSLR.
I&amp;rsquo;m using a trial version of Photomatix to perform the HDR processing and tone mapping which is why you&amp;rsquo;ll notice their watermark in the HDR image below.
I set the auto-bracketing option on the camera to shoot a normal exposure, a -2 stop exposure and a +2 stop exposure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Desktop Search Powershell Cmdlet</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2006/07/windows-desktop-search-powershell-cmdlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2006 21:23:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2006/07/windows-desktop-search-powershell-cmdlet/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft are introducing a new command line shell named PowerShell, previously known as Monad. The main difference between PowerShell and other shells like cmd, bash, ksh etc. is the pipelining and processing of objects as opposed to plain text.
I had previously used the Windows Desktop Search API to write a music browser and thought it would be useful to create a Windows Desktop Search Powershell cmdlet to allow users to query their search index from the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualearth Add in for Windows Media Center with Geocoded Pictures</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2005/11/virtualearth-add-in-for-windows-media-center-with-geocoded-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 21:48:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2005/11/virtualearth-add-in-for-windows-media-center-with-geocoded-pictures/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in my previous post I have a basic Virtual Earth add-in for Windows Media Center that works within the Media Center UI and is usable with the remote control.
I&amp;rsquo;ve now added support for integrating geocoded pictures with the Virtual Earth add-in. So next time someone asks you where a particular photo was taken while watching a slide show you can pop-up the Virtual Earth add-in which will center the map on the photo&amp;rsquo;s location and show a pushpin on the map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Earth Media Center Add In</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2005/11/virtual-earth-media-center-add-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2005 21:38:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2005/11/virtual-earth-media-center-add-in/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with a VirtualEarth HTML add-in for Windows Media Center. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a number of features lined up but I&amp;rsquo;ve been side tracked with other work so I&amp;rsquo;ve only got the basics implemented so far.
Remote control keys:
 Panning - use the arrow keys Zooming - use the channel +- keys Map Style - use the 1,2,3 keys to toggle map styles between road, aerial and hybrid  In addition since the text labels on the map have been sized for viewing on a regular monitor with a 2 foot experience I&amp;rsquo;ve added a local zoom option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indexing your complete browser history using MSN Desktop Search</title>
      <link>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2005/07/indexing-your-complete-browser-history-using-msn-desktop-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2005 21:56:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seanmcleod.github.io/2005/07/indexing-your-complete-browser-history-using-msn-desktop-search/</guid>
      <description>The MSN Desktop Search application is an evolutionary version of the standard Indexing Service that has been shipping as part of Windows since Windows 2000. They both make use of the same IFilter components to allow third parties to add indexing support for their file formats. One of the standard IFilter components is one that parses html documents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
